[roars]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
[squeaking]
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
"The mysterious unknown."
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words...
are called...
Hunters.
[theme song playing]
[Kurapika]
Take this to heart.
First,
a genuine Phantom Troupe tattoo
has the member's number inscribed
on the spider's back.
Second,
they don't bother tallying
the people they've killed
because it's irrelevant to them.
And third,
don't ever mention the Phantom Troupe
to me again.
If you do...
I will kill you with my bare hands.
TRICK x TO x THE TRICK
[narrator] Leorio, has volunteered
for the fourth round.
If he wins,
the group's victory is assured.
But will he be able to do it?
Hm.
Okay, it's time to end this.
Drag him off and send in
your next contender.
[Leroute giggles]
That's not possible.
Wait, what?
I said, I'm afraid we can't move him.
His match isn't over yet.
I don't get it,
how is the match not over?
What are you talking about?
He's still alive,
just unconscious.
Oh, don't you remember?
This was a fight to the death.
One of them had to either die
or admit defeat.
He's still alive
and he hasn't surrendered.
[laughs]
[huffs]
Talk about splitting hairs.
Maybe, but you've gotta admit
she's right.
-I'm with Killua.
-[Leorio grumbles]
That's how it is?
All right, Kurapika!
Get over there and put that loser
out of his misery.
I refuse.
[Leorio] What... huh?
[yelling]
What do you mean, refuse?
The fight was already over.
It was clear to me
that by the time I punched him,
he had already lost the will to fight.
I will not continue fighting a loser.
[yelling] Seriously?
What are we supposed to do?
'Cause those guys are claiming
the match hasn't even ended yet.
-I will leave that to him
-[Leorio] Huh?
He can decide his own fate
just as soon as he revives.
Come on!
We don't have that much time
and it's running out fast.
We can't afford to just sit around here
and wait.
My mind's made up, Leorio.
Oh, give me a break.
Hey, I can kill him
if you don't want to.
Killua?
Never killed anyone before, have you?
Are you scared?
Whether or not murder is frightening
has never entered my mind.
Regardless, this is a one-on-one battle.
You can't interfere.
Fine, I won't argue.
Except, if you were a team-player
you wouldn't be acting so selfish.
Hey! You said something useful
for once.
Do that more often!
Don't you know you're screwing up
our chances?
That's true,
but it doesn't change my position.
You stubborn little idiot.
[grumbles]
[yelling] All right,
time for majority rule.
Press O to kill the bastard
or X to let him live.
-[Leorio] Ready, and...
-[Tonpa snickers]
[watch beeps]
[screaming] Why in the hell
isn't it working?
I bet it's because we're the ones
asking the question.
[Leorio]
Huh?
It looks like the timers only work
for questions the Examiners ask.
I should have known.
In that case...
Okay! We'll do it the old-fashioned way.
Raise your hand
if you think we should finish him!
Me!
Hm. Oh!
Whose side are you on?
A minute ago you were trying to get him
to do it, just like I was.
We're in this together.
Where's your team spirit?
I just don't see the point.
Not like he's going to change his mind.
Hey Gon, why don't you think
we should kill the guy?
I'm with Kurapika on this one.
He was just about to surrender
when he knocked him out.
We should wait for him to wake up.
But there's no telling
how long that'll take.
I ought to just do it.
It's better if you don't force the issue.
You can't expect everybody
to share the same opinion.
Yeah, well nobody asked for yours, okay?
[Tonpa] Hey, come on.
If you wanted to put it to a vote,
you kind of did.
[Leorio] Huh?
Fine! If you want to wait, then wait.
Just see if I care.
Leorio, wait.
[Leorio, seething]
What is wrong with these people?
[Gon] He's sulking.
None of this matters
if we get stuck here.
Am I the only one who gets it?
Let's just leave him alone.
[Tonpa] Fools.
He's totally falling for it.
The trap of majority rule.
When five people
who barely know each other,
trying to decide on something,
you'd think voting would be the easiest
and most efficient way to do it.
People tend to think that voting
empowers the individual.
But the truth is, it can just as easily
turn the majority against the minority.
When someone keeps finding himself
in the minority,
his opinion is always rejected.
His anger, alienation, and frustration
make him resent antagonize the group.
Eventually, it tears the team apart.
After all, it's everyone for himself
in the Hunter Exam.
The feeling you get when
you're forced to follow a path
that other people set
can be a real pain.
It's annoying and makes you feel foolish.
But now he's all caught up in
the whole majority rule scenario,
and he's starting to use it
even when he doesn't have to.
And then, he made the mistake of
discussing the options
before he called for the vote.
He even asked for a show of hands.
Majority rule in its worst form.
When people are just pressing buttons
on their timers
they've got anonymity.
But when you raise your hand,
everybody knows exactly
what side you're on
and who's straying from the crowd.
And if you're in the minority,
there's no chance for a rebuttal.
When someone's opinions
are constantly rejected,
they feel like
their voice isn't being heard,
and the group breaks down.
And in our case it means
all five of us will fail the Exam.
It's just a matter of time.
[laughs]
[Sedokan] The atmosphere on the other side
is pretty grim.
[Leroute chuckles]
I've been waiting for you.
Hisoka.
I'm not an Examiner this year.
I'm here for revenge.
Ever since the last Exam,
all I've thought about is killing you.
And today I get payback.
[yelling]
For all the scars you gave me.
[laughs]
Those scars are but a symbol of
your incompetence as an Examiner.
Don't blame me for your inadequacies.
Shut up.
[chuckles]
Now prepare to die.
Two-blade style, huh?
All-direction four blade style!
[yelling]
Take this!
[Togari cries out]
I'm not done!
[huffs]
[Togari laughs]
Up, down, left, right,
you've got nowhere to run.
You're going to be cut up from every angle
by my endless barrage of blades.
You can't dodge my attacks forever.
I’m going to have you writhing in pain
and I'll savor every second.
[Hisoka] Hm.
And then you'll die, Hisoka!
[yells]
Dodging your attacks
would have been difficult, you're right.
Stopping your blades, however...
[Togari] Impossible!
It took me more than six months
of training
to master catching those blades.
My, my.
That was easier than expected.
Nice try but... it wasn't good enough.
[Togari breathes uneasily]
[screaming]
Damn it!
HUNTER GLOSSARY
HISOKA
[voice over PA]
First to pass the Third Phase
Hisoka, number 44.
Time elapsed, six hours, 17 minutes.
What's up, Gon, is something wrong?
Yeah.
Oh, I see.
[Killua] Hey...
It's looking more and more
like he's already dead.
What do you mean?
Well, he's been lying there for
a long time now
and he hasn't moved or anything.
[Leorio] Damn it.
It's impossible to tell
from this far away.
Hey you, we want to go over there
and check his body.
What was that?
He might be dead already
and we just want to see it for ourselves.
It's like I told you before,
he's only unconscious.
Yeah? Well how many hours do you think
we've been here?
You think we're just going to take
your word for it?
Care to make a wager, then?
Wager?
A wager on what?
[Leroute] On whether he's dead or alive.
What are the stakes?
What are you proposing?
[Leroute] Time.
[Leorio] Time?
[Leroute] We will settle our match
through gambling,
betting time instead of chips.
Look at the monitor on the wall.
We'll each have 50 hours
with which to wager.
And bets can only be placed
in ten hour increments.
We bet until one of our clocks
reaches zero.
Gambling with time, huh?
We'll take turns deciding
what to bet on.
If your credit reaches zero,
you will have 50 fewer hours
to escape the tower.
What if you hit zero first?
Fifty years will be added
to our sentences.
[gasps]
If you accept these terms,
I'll confirm whether he's alive or dead.
[Lippo] Leroute...
Sentenced to 112 years
for trafficking endangered wildlife
and breaking gambling laws.
This kind of match is right up her alley.
[Leorio]
Man, that woman is crazy.
Betting with her own jail time like that?
Consider your answer carefully.
If you lose,
we'll all have 50 fewer hours
to clear the tower.
Yeah, well nobody's asking you.
In case you forgot,
you're the one who got us into
this stupid damn mess in the first place.
Very well.
You won't hear another word from me.
[Leorio huffs]
Come on, we shouldn't be fighting
each other.
[Tonpa chuckles]
Keep it up, boys. Keep it up.
All right,
I accept your damn challenge.
Okay.
I chose our first bet
so you may set the ante.
Decide how many hours we'll wager on
whether he's alive or dead.
I bet ten hours that he's alive!
[chuckles]
What the hell?
He was just whining about Majitani
being dead.
[Leroute laughs]
All right then, let's confirm.
Playing it safe, aren't you?
I thought you weren't going to say
another word.
[Tonpa] Ten hours, huh?
[Leorio] It's the smart move.
Even if I'm wrong and he is dead,
then Kurapika will have won his round.
It's progress, at least.
If I bet that he's dead
and he's just out cold,
it's adding insult to injury.
[heart beats]
See, he's only unconscious.
[Leorio] So it seems.
[clock dings]
[Gon] Yes!
Leorio's taken an early lead.
-This is bad.
-[Gon] Huh?
Maybe he won't wake up
no matter how long we wait.
I don't understand.
Don't you remember,
when she walked by the guy on the floor?
What of it?
Well, I was pretty sure he was
already dead by then.
But when I thought about it,
I realized he's more useful to his team
alive.
As long as he stays unconscious.
See, if he doesn't wake up
before the time runs out,
their sentences will be shortened
by 72 years.
So, if he doesn't wake up at all,
then that means we--
That's my point.
So, that's been their intention all along.
[Leroute] Okay, it's our turn.
What would you like to bet on next?
Let me see...
I say we bet on whether or not
he's actually unconscious.
Huh?
[Gon] Oh, I get it.
Hm?
[Majitani]
Wait, What? This wasn't on the note.
What am I supposed to do now?
When I woke up there was
a note lying on the ground next to me.
It said,
“Keep pretending you’re out cold.
Hide this note in your mouth.”
I knew what I was supposed to do.
All I had to do was stay down
until the clock ran out
and we’d get seventy-two years off
our sentences.
But, now what?
Do I stay down and keep pretending?
[Leroute] All right.
I’ll bet twenty hours
that he really is out cold.
[Majitani] Okay, I got it!
That’s the play, then. I’ll just keep
acting like I’m unconscious.
[Leroute] The question is, how do you
propose we go about confirming this?
[Leorio] Oh...
It's simple, really.
Heavy bastard.
[Leorio grunts]
I figured I would just push him
off the edge.
[Majitani]
That’s the worst idea I’ve ever heard!
If he's really unconscious,
he’ll fall to his death
and that’s the end of it.
Are you insane?
His match hasn’t been decided yet.
There’s no way I can accept those terms!
Don't worry.
If he falls and kicks the bucket,
we’ll forfeit the match
giving you a grand total of two wins.
That work for you?
It does. Very well, then.
What was that?
Come on, don’t be ridiculous!
We’re talking about my life here!
[Leroute]
In that case, I’m changing my bet
I bet 40 hours
that he isn’t unconscious after all.
That’s everything I have left.
[chuckles] Little sneak.
Finally showing your true colors.
[heart beats]
[rhythm of heart increases steadily]
Guess I'll let go, then.
[yelling] Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on,
don't let go. I'm awake!
I'm awake.
[screams]
Wait! Wait!
I'm going to fall!
Good morning.
[chuckles]
[Majitani groans]
You’re both complete lunatics!
I’ve had enough!
I lost plain and simple, okay?
Forget reducing my sentence.
I’m going back to prison where it’s safe!
Dammit!
[Leroute]
You knew he was awake, didn't you?
Believe it or not, but I’m pre-med.
The way his eyes were moving
was a dead giveaway.
[clock beeps]
Even so,
you have only twenty hours remaining.
I know. But at least now we’re in
a better position with a two-one lead.
[beeping]
Now, let's keep this ball rolling.
The choice is yours,
so what’s it gonna be?
[narrator]
Majitani throws in the towel,
giving Gon and his friends
a two-to-one lead.
However, in the match
where they gamble for time,
they’re down 80 to 20.
It’s Leroute’s turn to pick the next bet.
But what will she choose?
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time.
"Trouble with the Gamble."
Bull... bull... bulldog!
[Gon barks]